Finding Aid for Institute for Social Research (University of Michigan) records 1936-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Survey Research Center (SRC) 1946-1980
  - Director's Files 1976-1990
    - Topical Files 1976-1990
      - 1980/81
        - SRC
          - Administration (Box 35)
          - Affirmative Action (Box 35)
          - Coding (Box 35)
          - Committee Membership (Box 35)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 35)
          - Computer Services Facility (Box 35)
          - Courses by SRC Staff (Box 35)
          - Economic Behavior (Box 35)
          - Evaluation Comments/Interim Studies (Box 35)
          - General (Box 35)
          - Family and Sex Roles (Box 35)
          - Field (Box 35)
          - Group Identify and Socialization (Box 35)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 35)
          - RFP Response (Box 35)
          - General (Box 35)
          - Sampling (Box 35)
          - Science and Society (Box 35)
          - Short Term Planning Committee (Box 35)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 35)
          - Space (Box 35)
          - Special Duty Assignments (Box 35)
          - Time Use Study (Box 35)
          - Understanding on Proposal to Develop Entrepreneurial Studies (Box 35)
          - Urban Environment (Box 35)
          - Word Processing Unit (Box 35)
      - 1981/82
        - ISR
          - Budget
            - General (Box 35)
            - General Funds (Box 35)
            - Teaching Funds (Box 35)
          - Center for Political Studies (Box 35)
          - Center for the Research Utilization of Scientific Knowledge (CRUSK) (Box 35)
          - Research Center for Group Dynamics (Box 35)
        - SRC
          - Administration (Box 35)
          - Affirmative Action (Box 35)
          - Computer Aided Telephone Interviewing (CATI) (Box 35)
          - Computer Services Facility (Box 35)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 35)
          - Director's Search (Box 35)
          - Economic Behavior (Box 35)
          - Field (Box 35)
          - Group Identify and Socialization (Box 35)
          - Interview Methodology (Box 35)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 35)
          - Publishing (Box 35)
          - Sampling Program (Box 35)
          - Science and Society (Box 35)
          - Short Term Planning (Box 35)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 35)
          - Social Indicators (Box 35)
          - Urban Environment (Box 35)
      - 1982/83
        - ISR (Box 36)
          - Budget
            - General Funds (Box 36)
            - Teaching Funds (Box 36)
        - SRC
          - Computer Aided Telephone Interviewing (CATI) (Box 36)
          - Computing Support Group (Box 36)
          - Courses Taught by SRC Staff (Box 36)
          - Family and Sex Roles (Box 36)
          - Field (Box 36)
          - Field Manager (Box 36)
          - Group Identity and Socialization (Box 36)
          - Interview Methodology (Box 36)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 36)
          - Policies (Box 36)
          - Program for Research on Black Americans (Box 36)
          - RFP Committee (Box 36)
          - Retirement Party (Box 36)
          - Sampling (Box 36)
          - Science and Society (Box 36)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 36)
          - Social Indicators (Box 36)
          - Special Duty Assignments (Box 36)
          - Survey of Consumers (Box 36)
          - Word Processing Committee (Box 36)
          - Youth In Transition/Monitoring the Future (Box 36)
      - 1983/84
        - Center on Oral Health and Behavioral Research (Box 36)
        - ISR
          - Budget (Box 36)
          - Business Office
            - Administrative Committee (Box 36)
            - General (Box 36)
            - Memos to Project Directors (Box 36)
          - CRUSK (Box 36)
          - General (Box 36)
          - Library (Box 36)
          - RCGD-National Study of Black Americans (Box 36)
          - Research Development (Box 36)
        - SRC
          - Computer Aided Telephone Interviewing (CATI) (Box 36)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 36)
          - Computing (Box 36)
          - Economic Behavior (Box 36)
          - Family and Sex Roles (Box 36)
          - Field (Box 36)
          - Group Identity and Socialization (Box 36)
          - Leave (Box 36)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 36)
          - Policies (Box 36)
          - Publishing (Box 36)
          - Sampling (Box 37)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 37)
          - Social Indicators (Box 37)
          - Support for Sociological Methods & Research (Box 37)
          - Technical Sections (Box 37)
          - Telephone Interviewing Facility (Box 37)
          - Urban Environment (Box 37)
      - 1984/85
        - Department of Sociology (Box 37)
        - ISR
          - Affirmative Action (Box 37)
          - Budget (Box 37)
          - Business Office (Box 37)
          - Business Office to Project Directors (Box 37)
          - Business Office Administration Committee (Box 37)
          - Center for Political Studies (Box 37)
          - General (Box 37)
          - General Funds (Box 37)
          - CRUSK (Box 37)
          - Space (Box 37)
          - Teaching Funds (Box 37)
          - Time Use Proposal (Box 37)
        - SRC
          - Angus Campbell Fellowship (Box 37)
          - Budget (Box 37)
          - Coding (Box 37)
          - Computer Aided Telephone Interviewing (CATI) (Box 37)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 37)
          - Cognition and Perception (Box 37)
          - Courses Taught by SRC Staff (Box 37)
          - Economic Behavior (Box 37)
          - Family and Demography (Box 37)
          - Field Office (Box 37)
          - Group Identity and Socialization (Box 37)
          - Interview Methodology (Box 37)
          - Long Range Planning Committee (Box 37)
          - Monitoring the Future (Box 37)
          - National Association of Business Economists (Box 37)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 37)
          - Organizational Psychology Search (Box 37)
          - Policies (Box 37)
          - Professional and Administrative/Clerical Advisory Committee (PAC) (Box 37)
          - Publishing (Box 37)
          - Recruitment (Box 37)
          - Revenue Projections (Box 37)
          - Sampling (Box 37)
          - Senior Staff (Box 37)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 37)
          - Social Indicators (Box 37)
          - Special Duty Assignment Plans (Box 37)
          - Technical Sections (Box 37)
          - Telephone Facility (Box 37)
          - Urban Environment (Box 37)
      - 1985/86
        - Department of Sociology (Box 51)
        - ISR
          - Affirmative Action (Box 38)
          - Budget (Box 38)
          - Business Office Administration Committee (Box 38)
          - Center for Political Studies (Box 38)
          - CRUSK (Box 38)
          - General Funds (Box 38)
          - Teaching Funds (Box 38)
        - SRC
          - Angus Campbell Fellowships (Box 38)
          - Budget (Box 38)
          - Coding (Box 38)
          - Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewing (Box 38)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 38)
          - Courses Taught by SRC Staff (Box 38)
          - Economic Behavior Program
            - General (Box 38)
            - Recruitment (Box 38)
          - Panel Study of Income Dynamics (Box 38)
          - Family and Demography (Box 38)
          - Family and Sex Roles (Box 38)
          - Field and Coding Advisory Committee (Box 38)
          - Field Office (Box 38)
          - Group Identity and Socialization (Box 38)
          - Human Subjects Review (Box 38)
          - Interview Methodology (Box 38)
          - Joint Appointments (Box 38)
          - Leave Plans (Box 38)
          - Monitoring the Future (Box 38)
          - National Association of Business Economists (Box 38)
          - Organizational Behavior (Box 38)
          - Policies (Box 38)
          - Professional and Administrative Committee (Box 38)
          - Promotion and Reappointment Reviews (Box 38)
          - Publishing (Box 38)
          - Research Plans for Research Scientists (Box 38)
          - Revenue Projections (Box 38)
          - Sampling (Box 38)
          - Scholarly Writing (Box 38)
          - Social Environment and Mental Health (Box 38)
          - Social Indicators (Box 38)
          - Space (Box 38)
          - Special Duty Assignments (Box 38)
          - Sponsored Conferences (Box 38)
          - Summer Institute (Box 38)
          - Technical Sections (Box 38)
          - Telephone Facility (Box 38)
          - Urban Environment (Box 38)
      - 1989/90
        - SRC
          - Angus Campbell Fellowship (Box 39)
          - Bibliography (Box 39)
          - Coding (Box 39)
          - Computer Support Group (Box 39)
          - Family and Demography (Box 39)
          - General Funds (Box 39)
          - Long Term Financial Support Plan (Box 39)
          - Miscellaneous Committees (Box 39)
          - Overhead (Box 39)
          - Professional and Administrative/Clerical Advisory Committee (Box 39)
          - Policies (Box 39)
          - Research Proposals by Non ISR Primary Research Staff (Box 39)
          - Study Director Search Committee (Box 39)
          - Summer Institute (Box 39)
          - Survey Operations Finances (Box 39)
          - Teaching Report (Box 39)
          - Telephone Facility (Box 39)
          - Visitors (Box 39)
  - Policies, Press Releases and Reports 1948-1987
    Policies, Press Releases and Reports includes policies for SRC, press releases on early research projects and reports from various SRC committees, primarily from the 1970s. Also included is an annual report for 1985/86. Policies and job descriptions for the years 1950 to 1987 are also in this portion of the records, although both do not exist for all years. Of note as well is a file of annual reviews done of senior staff in 1952/53.
    - Policies and Salaries
      - Policies 1950-1987 (Box 39)
      - Review of Senior Staff 1952-1953 (Box 39)
      - Salary Information 1961-1966 (Box 39)
    - Press Releases and Clippings
      - Clippings 1948-1964 (Box 39)
      - University of Michigan 1949-1961 (Box 39)
    - Reports and Recommendations
      - Committee Reports
        - Assistant in Research Positions at ISR 1972 (Box 39)
        - Committee on Privacy Report 1971 (Box 39)
        - Field Office Review Committee: Final Report 1971 (Box 39)
        - Recommendations Concerning the Executive Committee by the Committee on Representation and Elections 1971 (Box 39)
        - Report of the Committee on Employment 1972 (Box 39)
        - Report of the Committee on the Use of SRC Overhead Funds 1973 (Box 39)
        - Report of the ISR Communications Committee 1972 (Box 39)
        - Report of the Interim Surveys Evaluation Committee 1980 (Box 39)
        - Report of the Subcommittee on Staff Development 1971 (Box 39)
        - Staff Acquisition Committee Recommendations 1973 (Box 39)
        - Other (Box 39)
  - Project and Proposal Files 1946-1986
    Projects initiated from 1946 to 1968 and proposals presented for review from 1972 to 1986 are included in the Project and Proposal Files. In the project files, which are arranged by project number and chronologically, only the earliest date in the file, usually the date of the proposal, is listed. The files often contain the proposal as well as correspondence relating to the project, and sometimes progress reports. The early studies contain additional documentation, such as survey questions and tabulating information, some of it artefactual in nature. The proposals are arranged chronologically and contain proposals from 1972 to 1986 submitted to the SRC Executive Committee for review. Collectively, the Project and Proposal files provide an excellent overview of the topics and nature of research at SRC and how it changed over the years.
    - Project Files (by number)
      - Project Numbers-Historical (Box 40)
      - #1 U.S. Army Uniform Survey 1946, 2 folders (Box 40)
      - #5 Federal Reserve Liquid Asset Survey 1946 (Box 40)
      - #6 Office of Naval Research/Prudential 1946, 2 folders (Box 40)
      - #7 Attitudes Toward Russia 1946, 2 folders (Box 40)
      - #8 American Foreign Policy 1947, 3 folders (Box 40)
      - #14 Survey of Consumer Finances 1948 (Box 40)
      - #36 Library of Congress 1948 (Box 41)
      - #95 Maytag 1951 (Box 41)
      - #204 To Rockefeller Foundation for Support of Analysis of Data from a Field Experiment Undated (Box 41)
      - #205 National Institute of Health 1952 (Box 41)
      - #206 Office of Naval Research 1953 (Box 41)
      - #222 Study of Physiological Sciences 1953 (Box 41)
      - #214 Detroit Edison Accounting Department 1953 (Box 41)
      - #217 Air Force Managerial Personnel Study 1952 (Box 41)
      - #222 Survey of Physiological Science 1953 (Box 41)
      - #225 Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance 1954 (Box 41)
      - #231 Oil Industry Information Committee 1954 (Box 41)
      - #232 United Parcel Service Study 1956 (Box 41)
      - #234 Public Health Service 1954 (Box 41)
      - #237 Study of Scientific Personnel 1955 (Box 41)
      - #239, #240 League of Women Voters 1955 (Box 41)
      - #243 Community General Hospitals 1956 (Box 41)
      - #247 Imperial Oil (Box 41)
      - #252 Million Dollar Producer (Box 41)
      - #253 Dobeckmun Company 1960 (Box 41)
      - #255 Mental Health in Industry 1958 (Box 41)
      - #259 Carnegie Scientific Personnel 1960 (Box 41)
      - #261 League of Women Voters 1959 (Box 41)
      - #326 Medical Nursing 1964 (Box 41)
      - #327 Ecology of Employment Termination (Box 41)
      - #410 Educational Television (Box 41)
      - #422 Mental Health 1956, 2 folders (Box 41)
      - #434 Mental Health 1959 (Box 41)
      - #462 Dominican Republic (Box 41)
      - #476 Michigan Department of Mental Health 1964 (Box 41)
      - #486 Student Values 1965 (Box 41)
      - #520 Government Personnel (Box 41)
      - #605 Analysis of Mail Questionnaire Undated (Box 41)
      - #606 Consumers' Union (Box 41)
      - #607 Survey of Attitudes 1952 (Box 41)
      - #609 Port of New York Authority 1953 (Box 41)
      - #634 Michigan Bell Pilot Study 1955 (Box 42)
      - #620, #623, #633 Ford Foundation Study of Consumer Behavior 1954-1955 (Box 42)
      - #637 Gasoline Price Survey, 1955 (Box 42)
      - #638 Hope College Unemployment Compensation 1955 (Box 42)
      - #640 Survey of Consumer Finances 1955 (Box 42)
      - #641 First National City Bank 1955 (Box 42)
      - #642 Ford Foundation 1956 (Box 42)
      - #643 Michigan Bell 1955 (Box 42)
      - #646 Interim Economic Survey 1956 (Box 42)
      - #649 Interim Economic Survey 1956 (Box 42)
      - #657 Time, Inc. and Business Managers 1957 (Box 42)
      - #668 Banks 1959 (Box 42)
      - #669 Spring Omnibus (Box 42)
      - #670 Michigan Hospital and Medical Care 1959 (Box 42)
      - #675 Anglo-American Economics 1958 (Box 42)
      - #682 Small Loan Companies 1959 (Box 42)
      - #683 Large Savings Accounts 1959 (Box 42)
      - #872 Mednick Study on Creative Thinking 1960 (Box 42)
      - #889 Riegel Project 1961 (Box 42)
      - #932 Foreign Affairs 1965 (Box 42)
      - #946 Computer Techniques 1966 (Box 42)
      - #948 UM Calendar 1966 (Box 42)
    - Project Files (by date)
      - 1952, Study of Labor Organizations (Box 42)
      - 1953 Labor Union Study (Box 42)
      - 1955, Mental Health (Box 42)
      - 1962, Engineering as a Career (Box 42)
      - 1962, World Order (Box 42)
      - 1964, Growth of the American Family (Box 42)
      - 1966, Measuring Achievement-Related Motives (Box 42)
      - 1966, Journal of European Social Research (Box 42)
      - 1966, Proposal for a National Center Related to Race Relations and Minority Groups (Box 42)
      - 1967, Faxon/Youth in Michigan (Box 42)
      - 1968, FCC (Box 42)
      - Personality and Social Factors Related to Restricting Free Speech Undated (Box 42)
    - Project/Proposal Reviews
      - 1972-1973, 2 folders (Box 42)
      - 1972-March 1977, 9 folders (Box 43)
      - April 1977-June 1978, 16 folders (Box 44)
      - July 1978-August 1979, 14 folders (Box 45)
      - September 1979-May 1980, 10 folders (Box 46)
      - June-December 1980, 10 folders (Box 47)
      - January-June 1981, 8 folders (Box 48)
      - July 1984 (Box 48)
      - August 1984-March 1985, 8 folders (Box 49)
      - April-June 1985, 2 folders (Box 50)
      - November 1985-June 1986, 6 folders (Box 50)
- Photographs
  The Photographs subgroup contains only two images, one of an informal group at ISR in the 1980s and one of Eleanor Maccoby. A great number of photographs are still held by the Institute. Other are available in the University of Michigan News and Information record group held at the Bentley Historical Library.
  - General
    - Informal group shot, 1983(?), 5x7 color (Box 54)
      (Includes Tom Juster, James Morgan)
    - Eleanor Maccoby portrait Undated, black and white 5x7 (Box 54)
- ISR ADMINISTRATIVE
  - Director's Files
    - Topical Files
      - CRUSK 1976-1979 (Box 51)
    - University of Michigan
      - Department of Economics 1976-1983 (Box 51)
  - Assistant Director's Topical Files
    - Director's Search Committee 1976-1976 (Box 51)
    - ISR Director Review 1980 (Box 51)